Manchester, UK github.com/andreituta linkedin.com/in/andreituta

Andrei Nicolae Tuță

074 93935418 tuta.andrei96@gmail.com May 24, 2020

Professional Profile

Versatile and competitive professional with development experience ranging in size from small private projects to full scale applications, currently working on improving and expanding an online and mobile software e-commerce product. Driven by a passion for improving current understanding of technologies, expanding knowledge further and a desire for my team to succeed.

SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Java, Javascript, SQL, Bash, Python, Haskell
- Technologies and frameworks: AWS, EC2, S3, Springboot, Docker, Git, , Node, MySQL, MongoDB, Eclipse, JUnit, Mockito
- Spoken Languages: Romanian, English, French, Spanish

Professional History

• Aeroparker

Stockport, UK

Java Developer

Oct 2018 - present

- Spring expertise: Developed implementations of Spring based applications based on REST, Jooq, JWT and other tools.
- **BI tool**: Developed a BI tool used daily by a large number of clients to get yearly, monthly and hourly occupancy through REST calls and using D3.js visualisation.
- Java EE: Worked on developing new features for the Java core project, built using Apache Tomcat, AJAX technologies and JSP.

• Birmingham City University

Birmingham, UK

Technical Student Assistant

Sep 2017 - Jun 2018

- Student Assistant & Ambassador: Managed and aid groups of students during courses and activities. Tasks varied explaining programming concepts and active development to large scale organisation of an event and providing tech support if needed.
- Innovation Fest Mentor: Supervised two teams of students with the technical development, planning and pitching of their entries for a local technology contest, which they won.

• Oracle Romania

Bucharest, RO

Junior Database Administrator

Jun - Sep 2017

- Oracle DBA training: Received training covering topics such as administration, back-up, recovery and automation.
- MySQL: Participated in guided training on MySQL and Orace SQL

• Logika IT Solutions

Bucharest, RO

Junior Database Administrator

Jun - Aug 2016

• Summer internship: Worked as a trainee in a team of 4 people managing databases for multiple clients. Other responsibilities included writing reports and suggestions on ways to improve the work-flow and diminish cost.

EDUCATION

• Writer

• Birmingham City University

Data Analysis, Software Engineering & Database administration

Birmingham, UK

2015 - 2018

• Universidad de Alcala

Software Design, Cloud computing & Agile Development

Alcala de Henares, SP

Jan - Jun 2017

Extracurricular activities

• Volunteer CodeUp Stockport

Volunteering with helping our members at our monthly Meetups.

Medium

Jul 2019 - present

Writing articles featuring subjects related to programming & literature.

2017 - present

• Camp counselor

Assisted and organised programming workshops on Java, & Processing

URJ 6Points Sci tech

Jun - Aug 2018

• Outward Mobility Ambassador

Managing and recruiting students for international programs & social media development.

BCU CEBE Jan - Jun 2018

• President BCU RoSoc

Event planning, budgeting \mathcal{E} team management.

2016 - 2018

• Secretary Rotaract Club Birmingham

Event planning, PR & note-taking.

2015 - 2017